Have you heard the real story about
these ancient scrolls? It's crazy. In 79
AD, this volcano erupts and it buries
these two cities, turning 1,800 scrolls
into blocks of charcoal. But it also
preserves them for nearly 2,000 years,
making them the only surviving papyrus
library from the ancient world, but they
crumble when you try to open them. So,
in the past, scientists have gotten
around this by using X-rays to look
inside, which bounce off the tiny metals
in the ink, revealing hidden text. But
these scrolls are so old that these
scholars were using a carbon-based ink
where there's no metal to bounce off. So
instead, the scientists used a particle
accelerator to create an extremely
precise X-ray beam, creating 3D digital
slices at a resolution of two microns,
showing us the rolled layers of the
scroll. For reference, a strand of your
hair is 70 microns. And then a computer
system analyzed the spiral pattern to
flatten the layers out. And then they
use the specially trained AI to scan for
crackle patterns left behind when wet
ink dried thousands of years ago,
revealing hidden text, the ancient
musings of a philosopher on how to enjoy
your life. And now they're going to read
the rest. So to see what they say,
subscribe.